<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<reviews itemIdentifier="thn086"><review><reviewbody>If forced to classify this resplendent new Thinner release I would use the adjectives ÂatmosphericÂ and Âlounge-inspiredÂ. ÂRadio overBoardÂ goes beyond the more traditional Thinner house and dub-influenced sounds by blending exotic beats and rhythms with the more traditional sounds and instruments.  For an atmospheric flavor, listen to ÂMoonlight BathÂ were hints of dub and house meet with the organic sounds of ocean waves and birds or the almost drone-like ÂTake My Breath Â in which  smooth, flowing chords intermingle with transparent tones and odd, intermittent sounds.  For a slightly more lounge-like sound, listen as dissonantly played muted notes and light chords of ÂEnvironmental OsterathÂ merge with the nostalgic sounds of distant voices or try ÂCrossing the ChannelÂ where peculiar beats, deep bass, piano, and floating electronics entertain and relax the mind.  The varying rhythmic structure, choppy beats, loops, and sparse piano notes of ÂLoop the VibeÂ also contribute to a lounge-like atmosphere.  The trio ÂRadio overBoardÂ, ÂTrip IllusionÂ, and ÂRepriseÂ all put heavy emphasis on beats but not at the expense of each trackÂs idiosyncrasies.  Radio overBoardÂ has a melancholy tone with distorted electronics while ÂTrip IllusionÂ is an almost playful selection of sparingly played guitar notes and a simple, but moving, bass line.  The haunting female vocals, beautiful keyboards, and electronic noises that appear to emulate a saxophone make ÂRespriseÂ a keeper.  -LAJ-</reviewbody>
<reviewtitle>Atmospheric and Lounge-Inspired</reviewtitle>
<stars>5</stars>
<reviewer>LAJ</reviewer>
<createdate>2006-05-06 21:20:05</createdate>
<reviewdate>2006-05-06 21:20:05</reviewdate>
</review>
<review><reviewbody>Great album... love the sound and the mixing. Beautiful bass thumps, interesting arrangements. Not the greatest choice in synth sounds, but none the less a great album. </reviewbody>
<reviewtitle>Very nice</reviewtitle>
<stars>4</stars>
<reviewer>johnny i</reviewer>
<createdate>2006-05-25 07:19:37</createdate>
<reviewdate>2006-05-25 07:19:37</reviewdate>
</review>
<info><num_reviews>2</num_reviews>
<avg_rating>4.50</avg_rating>
</info>
</reviews>
